舰长日志
Captain's Log :
星历4372.5
Star date 4372.5 .
在一次绝密外交任务中
On a top-secret diplomatic mission,
我们进入了特伦星系
the Enterprise has entered the Tellun star system.
维持通讯中断了
Maintaining communications blackout,
我们把佩特里带上了船
we have taken aboard Petri,
来自外行星
Ambassador from Troyius,
特洛伊乌斯的大使
the outer planet,
现在正接近内行星，伊拉斯
and are now approaching the inner planet Elas.
一些书呆子气的星际舰队官僚
Some desk bound Starfleet bureaucrat
下达了这些间谍命令
cut these cloak-and-dagger orders.
是，但为什么要遮遮掩掩？
Aye, but why the secrecy?
该星系受联邦控制
This star system's under Federation control.
它在边境地区，斯科特先生
It's in a border area, Mr. Scott.
克林贡人也声称拥有管辖权
Klingons also claim jurisdiction.
就我看来
From what I've seen,
不值得为争抢
it's not worth fighting about.
我们为什么在这里，舰长？
Why are we here, Captain?
我的命令是配合佩特里大使
My order is to cooperate with Ambassador Petri
处理他在这里的任务的所有事项
in all matters pertaining to his mission here.
[乌乎拉] 舰桥呼叫柯克舰长
[Uhura] Bridge to Captain Kirk.
斯科提
Scotty.
我是柯克，怎么了？
Kirk here. What is it?
舰长，我收到了来自伊拉希人的信号
Captain, I have a signal from the Elasians.
他们准备登船
They're ready to beam aboard.
他们要求对迟到做出解释
They demand an explanation for the delay.
要求？什么迟到？将他们传送到船上
Demand? What delay? All right. Beam them aboard.
听起来是典型的伊拉希人
Sounds typical of the Elasians.
进行调查的科学家说
The scientists who made the initial investigation
这些人恶毒且傲慢
reported the men were vicious and arrogant.
这只是负面的部分，史波克先生
That's just the negative part, Mr. Spock.
我看过那些记录
I've been over those records.
那里的女人很特别
Now, the women, they're supposed to be something very special.
她们有一种
They're supposed to have
微妙的神秘力量
a kind of subtle, mystical power
让男人疯狂
that drives men wild.
佩特里大使，能不能别废话
Ambassador Petri, would you drop all this nonsense
告诉我这是关于什么的
and tell me what this is about?
那必须等多尔曼上船
That must wait until the Dohlman is aboard.
多尔曼？什么是多尔曼？
Dohlman? What the devil is a Dohlman?
我的人民最害怕和最讨厌的东西
The thing most feared and hated by my people.
我们最致命的敌人
Our most deadly enemy.
[传送装置传送]
[Transporter Beam]
欢迎
Welcome.
我是特洛伊乌斯的大使佩特里
I am Petri, Ambassador of Troyius.
我是柯克舰长
I'm Captain Kirk.
我指挥这艘飞船
This ship is under my command.
这里有一个特洛伊人
There's a Troyian here.
我必须确定，一切都是安全的
I must know that all is secure
在多尔曼上船之前
before the Dohlman is brought on board.
这艘船是安全的…
This ship is secure ...
我们已准备好
and we're prepared
应对任何不友好行为
for any hostile action.
传送
Energize.
向伊拉斯的多尔曼致敬
Do honour to the Dohlman of Elas.
荣耀归于伊兰
Glory to Elaan,
伊拉斯的多尔曼
Dohlman of Elas.
宇宙
Space ...
最后的边疆
the final frontier.
这些是星舰企业号的航程
These are the voyages of the star ship Enterprise.
它的五年任务：
Its five-year mission:
探索未知的新世界
to explore strange new worlds,
寻找新生命和新文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇踏前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
特洛伊乌斯的伊兰
Elaan of Troyius
你们可以起身了
You may stand.
防弹衣
Body armour.
核武器
Nuclear weapons.
并非没有先例，舰长
Not without precedent, Captain.
记住…
Remember that --
我没有允许你们说话
Permission to speak was not given.
你统治这艘船？
You rule this ship?
我是大副
I am the first officer.
这是詹姆斯·柯克舰长
This is Captain James Kirk.
殿下，我是佩特里
Your Glory, I am Petri.
以我人民的名义…
In the name of my people --
我们都知道你的任务
Your mission is known to us.
舰长，你现在可以
Captain Kirk, you have now permission
带我们去住处了
to show us to our quarters.
好的，现在稍等
Well, now, Just a moment.
我们必须要
There's going to have to be
相互理解
some kind of understanding.
拜托！
Please ...
我的大副史波克先生
My first officer Mr. Spock
会带你去你的住处
will show you to your quarters.
大使我想和你说句话
Ambassador, I'd like to speak to you.
[伊兰] 我还没说可以走
[Elaan] You have not been dismissed.
我可以要求离开吗？
May I have your permission to go?
你现在可以走了
You are now dismissed.
好的，谢谢
Well, thank you.
大使
Ambassador.
大使，是时候
Ambassador, I think it's time
告诉我发生什么了
you told me what's going on.
那个…生物，伊兰
That creature ... Elaan
将成为我们统治者的妻子
is to be the wife of our ruler
带来和平
to bring peace.
我们的两个敌对的星球
Our two warring planets
现在拥有相互毁灭的能力
now possess the capability of mutual destruction.
必须找到某种共存的方法
Some method of coexistence must be found.
我明白了
I see.
所以我们回特洛伊乌斯
So, we go back to Troyius?
是的，但是慢慢走，舰长
Yes. Ah, but slowly, Captain.
我需要时间
I will need time.
在我们到达那里之前
Before we reach there,
必须教她文明礼貌
she must be taught civilized manners.
以她现在的样子
In her present condition,
我的人民永远不会接受她
my people would never accept her.
你要当她的老师？
And you are to be her teacher?
那是给我的命令
Those are my orders.
我必须要求你和你的船员
I must ask you and your crew
尊重，或者至少容忍他们的傲慢
to respect, or at least tolerate, their arrogance.
摩擦必须保持在最低限度
Friction must be kept at a minimum.
好的，我能理解
Yes, that I can understand.
另一件事你应该明白，舰长
Another thing you should understand, Captain.
你和我一样处于危险中
You have as much at stake as I have.
你的上级说
Your superiors made the statement
这次任务要是失败
that failure of this mission
对联邦和我们两个星球来说
would be as catastrophic for Federation planning
都是灾难性的
as it would be for our two planets.
以接受这样的女王为代价换取和平
To gain peace at the price of accepting such a queen
不是胜利
is no victory.
我会送她 我带来的正式礼物
I will take her the official gifts I bear.
也许那会缓和她的情绪
Perhaps that will soften her mood.
契科夫先生，设定前往特洛伊乌斯的航线
Mr. Chekov, lay in a course for Troyius.
苏鲁先生，脉冲引擎
Mr. Sulu, impulse drive.
速度系数.037
Speed factor .037.
脉冲引擎，舰长？
Impulse drive, Captain?
是的，没错，苏鲁先生
Yes, that's correct, Mr. Sulu.
亚光系数.037
Sub light factor .037.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
舰长
Captain,
你不用曲速引擎？
you'll not be using the warp drive?
全程用脉冲？
All the way on impulse?
这将花费大量时间
That'll take a great deal of time.
你赶时间吗，斯科特先生？
You in a hurry, Mr. Scott?
不
No.
舰长，多尔曼
Captain, the Dohlman is dissatisfied
对提供的住处不满意
with the quarters provided.
他们怎么了，史波克？
What's the matter with them, Mr. Spock?
我不知道
I do not know,
所有伊拉希人看起来都很不理性
but all the Elasians seem most irrational.
我放弃了我的宿舍，因为…
I gave up my quarters because...
是的，我感谢你的牺牲，乌乎拉上尉
Yes, I appreciate your sacrifice, Lieutenant Uhura.
我会亲自和她谈谈
I'll talk to her myself.
猪猡！收回你的礼物
Swine! Take back your gifts!
殿下
Your Glory ...
这是你的婚礼拖鞋
these are your wedding slippers.
你的统治者收买不了
Your ruler cannot buy the favours
埃拉斯的多尔曼的欢心
of the Dohlman of Elas.
这…这是你的婚礼礼服
This ... This is your wedding dress,
来自新郎母亲的礼物
a gift from the bridegroom's mother.
我不要他的任何东西！
I want nothing of his!
这…这是最珍贵的皇家珠宝…
This ... This is the most prized of royal jewels ...
戴在你优美的脖子上
for your lovely neck.
我会勒死，如果我把
I would strangle if I was to put
一只特洛伊狗的礼物戴在脖子上
the gift of a Troyian dog around my neck.
克莱顿，谁允许他进来的？
Kryton, by whose permission did he enter?
他是应您的传召来的
He came in answer to your summons.
我知道你对住处不满意
I understand you're not happy with your quarters.
住处？
Quarters?
[玻璃碎裂]
[Glass Breaks]
是的，一点都不满意
Yes, not happy at all.
我是一只柔弱的特洛伊小鹿
Am I a soft Troyian fawn
需要枕头坐吗？
to need pillows to sit on?
还有这些可笑的女性装饰
And these ridiculous female trappings.
冒犯了我的眼睛
They are an offense to my eyes.
我的通讯官慷慨地腾出房间
My communications officer generously vacated the rooms
希望你能满意
hoping you would find it satisfactory.
我不这么认为
I do not find them so.
而且我更不满意他
I find him even less satisfactory.
一定要让那个大使呆在你的船上
Must my bitterness be compounded with that ridiculous ambassador
增加我的痛苦吗？
aboard your ship?
我向殿下解释说
I explained to Her Glory
她的贵族议会和特洛伊乌斯法庭
that her council of nobles and the Troyius Tribunal
共同同意，我应该教导…
Jointly agreed that I should instruct ...
让她熟悉
make her acquainted
我们人民的习俗和礼仪
with the customs and manners of our people.
克莱顿
Kryton!
把他弄走！
Remove him!
带上那些垃圾！
And take that garbage with you!
他居然敢
He dare to suggest
让我学习他人民的奴性！
that I adopt the servile manners of his people!
殿下似乎没有
Your Glory doesn't seem to be responding
响应指令
to instruction.
我永远不会原谅议会
I will never forgive the council
让我经受这种折磨
for putting me through this torture.
你是应我的要求来解决住处问题的吗？
Were you responding to my demand for better quarters?
没有更好的了
There are none better.
我建议你凑合着住
I suggest you make do with these.
你建议？
You suggest?
没有空余的房间了
There are no more available.
但如果这是你获得满足感的唯一方式
But if that's the only way you can get gratification,
我会让人把整间屋子都装满能砸的东西
I'll arrange to have the whole room filled from floor to ceiling with breakable objects.
我不会让你羞辱我的！
I will not be humiliated!
那就举止文明一点
Then act in a civilized fashion.
我没有允许你离开
I did not give you permission to leave!
我没有请求允许
I didn't ask for any.
哦！
Oh!
舰长，我想联系我的政府
Captain, I wish to contact my government.
我无法完成我的使命
I cannot fulfil my mission.
这是对我们统治者的侮辱
It would be an insult to our ruler
把这个积习难改的怪物当新娘带回去
to bring this incorrigible monster as a bride!
大使！这应该是个和平任务
Ambassador! This is supposed to be a peaceful mission.
我们之间不可能有和平
There cannot be peace between us.
我们自欺欺人了
We have deluded ourselves.
舰长，当我靠近他们时，我不想要和平
Captain, when I am near them, I do not want peace.
我想杀了他们！
I want to kill them.
你和她一样坏
You're as bad as she is.
你们不需要彼此喜欢
It's not required that you like each other.
做你的工作
Just do your job.
工作？这份工作是不可能完成的
The job? The job is impossible.
我们无法与我们厌恶的人
We cannot make peace
和平相处
with people we detest.
不要试图互相残杀
Stop trying to kill each other!
然后友好相处
Then worry about being friendly.
但如果她不听我的…
But if she won't listen to me ...
那就让她听，大使！
Then make her listen, Ambassador.
用别的方法
Use a different approach.
别用外交辞令
Stop being so diplomatic.
她崇尚强权
She respects strength.
强硬点
Go in strong.
起初它似乎是一个传感器幽灵
At first it appeared to be a sensor ghost,
但我已经对所有仪器进行了检查
but I've run checks on all the instrumentation.
所有设备都运行良好
All the equipment is functioning perfectly.
氢云反射？
Hydrogen cloud reflection?
该地区没有
None in this area.
没有东西能解释
Nothing that would account for it.
幽灵断断续续地出现
The ghost appears intermittently.
推测？
Speculation?
没有，舰长
None, Captain.
数据不足
Insufficient data.
这不是仪器故障
It's not an instrument malfunction.
这不是自然现象的反射
It's not a reflection from a natural phenomenon.
一艘飞船？
A spaceship?
[斯科提] 轮机部呼叫柯克舰长
[Scotty] Engineering to Captain Kirk.
我是柯克
Kirk here.
舰长，我懂你说的
Captain, I know what you said
尊重的意思
about showing respect,
但是必须让这些人
but must I have these persons
在我的设备周围闲逛吗？
fool around with my equipment?
坚持一下，斯科提
Hang on, Scotty.
不管多难忍都要友好
Be pleasant no matter how much it hurts.
我马上下来
I'll be right down.
我们现在只靠脉冲引擎运行
We're only running on impulse engines now.
通常我们只用曲速引擎
Ordinarily, we use the warp engines exclusively.
嗯…我想…
Well ... I suppose ...
姑娘…
lassie ...
就算是我们的脉冲引擎
that even our impulse engines
看起来也更快
must seem fast
与你们的核推进装置相比
compared to your nuclear propulsion units.
我们感兴趣的
We are interested
是这艘船如何在战斗中使用
in how the ship is used in combat,
而不是它的引擎
not in what drives it.
引擎是机械师和仆人们操心的
Engines are for mechanics and menials.
仆人？
Menials?
没有引擎
Without engines,
就没有战斗或…
there'd be no fighting or ...
[柯克] 斯科特先生！
[Kirk] Mr. Scott!
你应该告诉我
I wish you had told me
你想要参观轮机部
you wanted a tour of the engineering department.
我们没有在这艘船上的自由吗？
Do we not have the freedom of this ship?
我们准许你的船员
We have granted your crew the permission
不用在我们面前下跪
not to kneel in our presence.
你还想要什么？
What else do you want?
礼貌，记得吗？
Courtesy. Remember?
礼貌不适合低等人
Courtesy is not for inferiors.
礼貌适用于这里的每个人
Courtesy is for everyone around here,
不懂礼貌你会发现你将无法
and you'll find you won't be able
在特洛伊乌斯上生存
to exist on Troyius without it.
斯科特先生，我们的轮机长
Mr. Scott, our chief engineer,
向你展示了他的部门
has shown you his engineering department.
这是一种礼貌
That's a courtesy.
你该说谢谢回应
You respond by saying thank you.
[对讲机哨声]
[Intercom Whistles]
[史波克] 舰桥呼叫舰长
[Spock] Bridge to Captain.
我是柯克
Kirk here.
那个传感器幽灵越来越近了
That sensor ghost is moving closer.
我来了
On my way.
现在失去联系了
Lost contact now.
[开门]
[Door Opens]
舰长，我们对这个物体进行了短暂定位
Captain, we had a momentary fix on the object,
足以确定它是一艘宇宙飞船
long enough to establish it was a spaceship.
谁的？
Whose?
还没有数据
No data yet.
[苏鲁] 舰长！
[Sulu] Captain!
距离方位，长官
Distant bearing, sir.
标记73.5
Mark 73.5.
主屏幕
Main screen.
最大放大倍数
Extreme magnification.
我们的幽灵出现了
Our ghost has materialized.
一艘克林贡军舰
A Klingon warship.
有变化吗，史波克先生？
Any change, Mr. Spock?
没有，舰长
Negative, Captain.
克林贡飞船已进入接触范围
The Klingon ship has simply moved into contact range.
她在根据我们调整
She is pacing us,
精确匹配我们的亚光速
precisely matching our sub light speed
在平行航线上
and on a parallel course.
警卫呼叫柯克舰长
Security to Captain Kirk.
我是柯克，怎么了？
Kirk here. What is it?
多尔曼的住处有骚乱，长官
Disturbance in the Dohlman's quarters, sir.
我来了
On my way.
舰长，是佩特里大使
Captain, it's Ambassador Petri.
他们拒绝解释他们发生了什么
They refuse to explain what's happening with them.
殿下没有召见你
Her Glory has not summoned you.
克莱顿，把那头特洛伊猪弄走
Kryton, remove that Troyian pig.
伤口很深，吉姆
It was a deep wound, Jim.
他失了很多血，但他会康复的
He lost a lot of blood, but he'll recover.
如果我康复了
If I recover,
也不会感谢你，舰长
it will be no thanks to you, Captain.
我说和她谈谈，不是和她打架
I said talk with her, not fight with her.
我就知道不该
I should've known better
手无寸铁地和她谈话
than to talk to her unarmed,
是你强迫我的
but you forced me.
我认为你该对此负责
I hold you responsible for this.
我听说过不情愿的新娘
Well, I've heard of reluctant brides,
但这很荒谬
but this is ridiculous.
柯克舰长
Captain Kirk.
我可以和你谈谈吗，长官？
May I speak with you, sir?
好的，当然
Yes. Certainly.
一条来自星际舰队指挥部的消息
A message just came from Starfleet Command.
属于甲级安全并且加密了
It was class-A security and scrambled.
我把它放入了解码器
I put it through the decoder.
是什么？
What was it?
联邦高级专员
The Federation high commissioner
正在前往特洛伊乌斯参加皇室婚礼
is on his way to Troyius to attend the royal wedding.
大使，如果伊拉希亚女人那么凶狠
Ambassador, if Elasian women are that vicious,
为什么男人对她们如此着迷？
why are men so overwhelmingly attracted to them?
我的意思是
I mean,
她们有什么魔法？
what magic do they possess?
不是魔法
It's not magic.
是生物化学
It's biochemical.
一个男人一旦碰到
A man whose flesh is once touched
伊拉希亚女人的眼泪
by the tears of a woman of Elas
他的心便会永远被奴役
has his heart enslaved forever.
大使，有一个额外的问题
Ambassador, there's an added complication.
联邦高级专员
The Federation high commissioner
将要参加婚礼
will be attending the wedding.
当他知道新娘试图
The fat will be in the fire
谋杀新郎的大使时
when he learns the bride Just tried to murder
会火上浇油
the groom's ambassador.
不会有婚礼
There will be no wedding.
我不会让我们的统治者娶那个怪物
I would not have our ruler marry that monster
哪怕整个银河系都指望它
if the entire galaxy depended on it,
我也不会与你打交道了
and I will have nothing further to do with you.
我不是要你和我打交道
I'm not asking you to have anything to do with me.
和她一起做你的工作
Do your job with her.
他什么时候能站起来？
How long before he's on his feet?
几天，至少一周，吉姆
A few days. A week, at least, Jim.
你害我这样，舰长
Here you put me, Captain.
那我就留在这里
Here I will stay.
我没有什么要对你说的了
I have nothing further to say to you.
所以……
So ...
佩特里大使要康复了
Ambassador Petri is going to recover?
那太糟糕了
That is too bad.
消息送到， 你可以走了
You have delivered your message. Now you may go.
没有什么比这更让我高兴了，殿下
Nothing would please me more, Your Glory,
但你鲁莽的性格…
but your impetuous nature ...
你的特洛伊猪猡在我的住所
Your Troyian pig was in my quarters
未经任何许可
without any permission,
于是我捅了他一刀
so I stabbed him.
身为特洛伊人就是原罪
Just to be Troyian is enough.
你们伊拉希亚人 以自己是一个战士而自豪
You Elasians pride yourselves on being a warrior people.
你必须了解纪律
You must understand discipline,
才能下达和接收命令
to be able to give and take orders.
我的命令是带你
My orders are to take you to Troyius
去特洛伊乌斯结婚
to be married
并监督你学习特洛伊的习俗
and to see that you learn Troyian customs.
我鄙视特洛伊人
I despise Troyians.
和他们接触让我觉得被玷污
Any contact with them makes me feel soiled.
根据我的经验
It's been my experience
当人们相互了解时
that the prejudices people feel about each other
他们对彼此的偏见就会消失
disappear when they get to know each other.
我不这么认为
It's not my experience.
我们仍然面临着同样的问题
Well, we're still faced with the same problem.
问题？
Problem?
是的，你学习特洛伊习俗
Yes, the problem of your indoctrination
和礼仪的问题
to Troyian customs and manners.
我已经解决了这个问题
I have eliminated that problem.
你解决了老师
You have eliminated the teacher.
问题还在
The problem still remains.
哦
Oh.
那我们如何解决这个问题？
And how do we solve the problem?
给你……
By ...
找一个新老师
giving you a new teacher.
告诉我， 你能教我什么？
Tell me, what can you teach me?
餐桌礼仪，比如
Table manners, for one thing.
这是一个盘子
This is a plate.
它能盛食物
It contains food.
这是一把刀
This is a knife.
它能切食物
It cuts the food.
这是一个玻璃杯
- This is a glass.
别烦我！
- Leave me!
不管你喜不喜欢，你都要学
Like it or not, you're going to learn what you've been ordered!
立即送我回伊拉斯
You will return me to Elas immediately.
那不可能
That's impossible.
我命令一切都是可能的
Everything I order is possible.
这是我们要解决的第一个问题
That's the first problem we'll work on.
然后我们让你准备去特洛伊乌斯
Then we'll get you ready to go to Troyius.
我不要去特洛伊乌斯
I will not go to Troyius,
我不要嫁给一个特洛伊人
I will not be mated to a Troyian,
而且我不会被羞辱
and I will not be humiliated,
被送给一只绿猪
and I will not be given to a green pig
作为停战的贿赂
as a bribe to stop a war!
你享受成为多尔曼的特权
You enjoy the privileges and prerogatives of being a Dohlman.
就得尽你的义务
Then be worthy of them.
如果你不想尽
If you don't want the obligations
头衔带来的义务
that go along with the title,
那就放弃它
then give it up.
没人敢这样跟我说话
Nobody speaks to me that way.
那是你的另一个问题
That's another one of your problems.
没人告诉你 你是一个未开化野蛮人，
Nobody's told you that you're an uncivilized savage,
一个女人外表的恶毒孩童
a vicious child in a woman's body,
一个傲慢的怪物
an arrogant monster!
你不该这么对待
That's no way to treat someone
对你说实话的人
who's telling you the truth.
明天的课是关于礼貌的
Tomorrow's lesson will be on courtesy.
上尉，开启呼叫频率
Lieutenant, open up the hailing frequency,
表明身份
Identify us,
并询问克林贡人的意图
and ask the Klingon his intentions.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
舰长，克林贡船只
Captain, no response from the Klingon vessel
在任何频道上都没有回应
on any channel.
我知道了，好的，上尉
I see. All right, Lieutenant.
监听所有频率
Monitor all frequencies.
相位炮待命
Phaser crews stand by.
保持黄色警报
Maintain yellow alert.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
啊！
Aah!
任何人不得进入多尔曼的住处
No one may enter the Dohlman's presence.
克莱顿在哪里？
Where's Kryton?
他在忙
On business.
任何人不得进入多尔曼的住处
No one may enter the Dohlman's presence.
能不能告诉殿下
Will you tell Her Glory
柯克舰长请求拜访？
Captain Kirk requests the honour of a visit?
多尔曼承诺我会被鞭打至死
The Dohlman has promised I'll be whipped to death
如果我让柯克舰长走过那扇门
if I let Captain Kirk pass through that door.
谢谢，史波克先生
Thank you, Mr. Spock.
他们醒了，把他们带去警卫室
When they wake up, take them to Security Holding.
舰长，你对情况的分析很完美
Captain, your analysis of the situation was flawless,
预料到她会不让你进去
anticipating that she would deny you admittance.
但是你得出结论的逻辑让我无法理解
However, the logic by which you arrived at your conclusion escapes me.
史波克先生，你们星球上的女人是合乎逻辑的
Mr. Spock, the women on your planet are logical.
那是银河系唯一
That is the only planet in this galaxy
可以做到这一点的行星
that can make that claim.
[开门]
[Door Opens]
你竟然敢碰皇室成员
You dare touch a member of the royal family.
只是自卫
Only in self-defense.
现在你还要不要动手动脚？
Now, are you going to behave or not?
你现在的行为是死罪
The penalty is death for what you are doing.
我们不在伊拉斯
We're not on Elas.
我们在我的星舰上
We're on my star ship.
这里我说了算
I command here.
我警告你，舰长，不许再碰我
You are warned, Captain, never to touch me again.
如果我再碰你，殿下
If I touch you again, Your Glory,
那就是在执行一种古老的地球习俗，打屁股
it'll be to administer an ancient Earth custom called a spanking,
一种惩罚
a form of punishment
被宠坏的孩子的方式
administered to spoiled brats.
你可以走了
You have my leave to go.
你忘了，殿下
You forget, Your Glory,
我们还没开始上礼仪课
we haven't started your lesson in courtesy.
你什么都教不了我，舰长
You can teach me nothing, Captain.
哪怕要在这里呆上十光年
If I have to stay here for 10 light-years,
我也不要和你接触而玷污我
I will not be soiled by any contact with you.
很好，那我派史波克先生或麦考伊医生来
Very well. I'll send in Mr. Spock or Dr. McCoy.
无论怎样，你都要为特洛伊乌斯做好充分的准备
Either way, you'll be properly prepared for Troyius
按照议会，统治者和官僚的命令
as ordered by councils, rulers, and bureaucrats.
舰长
Captain ...
你可以教我一件事
there is one thing you can teach me.
不，你一开始就是对的
No, you were right the first time.
我没有东西可以教你
There's nothing I can teach you,
没有事情是你不知道的
there is nothing you do not know.
我不知道如何让人们喜欢我
I don't know how to make people like me.
我不想让每个人都讨厌我
I don't want everybody to hate me.
嗯，不是…
Well, it's not ...
不是人们讨厌你
it's not that people hate you.
只是人们不喜欢被当作
It's just that people don't like to be treated
好像他们不存在
as though they don't exist.
哦……
Ohh ...
它，呃…
It's, uh ...
变得非常，呃…
gotten very, uh ...
一定是通风系统出了问题
Something must've gone wrong with the ventilation system.
舰长……
Captain ...
对不起，殿下
Pardon me, Your Glory.
短暂休息一下
There will be a short recess.
舰长？
Captain.
舰长
Captain,
那个叫做打屁股的古老习俗……
that ancient Earth custom called spanking ...
是什么？
what is it?
它是，呃…
It's, um ...
It's, uh ...
我们稍后再谈
We'll talk about it later.
舰桥呼叫柯克舰长
Bridge to Captain Kirk.
史波克先生…
Mr. Spock ...
传感器捕捉到它了，上尉
I have it on my sensor, Lieutenant.
舰桥呼叫柯克舰长
Bridge to Captain Kirk.
请回答
Come in, please.
柯克舰长，请回答
Captain Kirk, please answer.
我是柯克
Kirk here.
哦，舰长，我正在企业号内部
Oh, Captain, I'm picking up transmission
捕捉到了信号传输
from inside the Enterprise.
它位于瞄准克林贡船只的密集光束上
It's on a tight beam aimed at the Klingon vessel.
在企业号内部？
Inside the Enterprise?
你能精确定位吗？
Can you pinpoint it?
我是史波克，舰长
Spock here, Captain.
我正在进行三角测量
I'm triangulating now.
它来自轮机部
It's coming from the engineering section.
警卫去轮机部
Security to Engineering.
入侵警报
Intruder alert.
所有甲板安全警报
Security alert to all decks.
通话完毕
Kirk out.
没有人看到他
Nobody saw him,
但那个家伙不知怎地偷偷溜进了这里
but that devil sneaked in here some way.
沃森因抓住他而被杀
Watson must've caught him and was killed.
他有这个
He had this.
看起来像某种发射器
Looks like some sort of transmitter.
是克林贡人，老骨头？
It's Klingon. Bones?
舰长
Captain.
脖子断得很干脆
Neck snapped clean.
你给克林贡飞船发了什么信号？
What kind of signal did you send the Klingon ship?
舰长，你知道我不会告诉你的
Captain, you must know I will tell you nothing.
我们的审讯技巧比你所能忍受的更令人痛苦
Our interrogation techniques are more excruciating than you're capable of.
是的，我知道你可以抵抗身体上的折磨
Yes, I'm aware you're trained to resist any form of physical torture.
柯克呼叫史波克
Kirk to Spock.
我是史波克，舰长
Spock here, Captain.
史波克先生，是克莱顿在发射信号
Mr. Spock, it was Kryton transmitting.
他不肯开口
He refuses to talk.
我需要你来进行瓦肯心灵融合
I'll need you for the Vulcan mind meld.
舰长，对不起，他似乎…
Captain, I'm sorry. He seemed --
他想掩盖什么？
What was he trying to cover
重要到可以为其付出生命
that was so important he had to die for it?
斯科提，他进入轮机部
Scotty, he didn't come into Engineering
不仅仅为了使用发射器
Just to use the transmitter.
我要你检查你的每个继电器
I want you to heck every relay you've got.
舰长，你必须意识到时间…
Captain, you must realize the time ...
不要浪费时间和我说这个，快去做
Don't waste the time telling me about it. Get to it.
是的
Aye.
克莱顿出身于一个贵族家庭
Kryton was of a noble family.
他爱我，想娶我
He loved me and wanted to marry me.
当他听说婚礼计划的公告时，他非常生气
He was furious when he heard of the announcement of the wedding plans.
他因为嫉妒而投靠克林贡人？
He sold out to the Klingons because of jealousy?
也许吧
Probably.
但为什么要谈不重要的事情呢？
But why speak of unimportant matters
我们来说说我们的事
when we can speak about us?
外面有一艘克林贡军舰
There's a Klingon warship out there.
他们来干什么？
What's their involvement?
当然，这一切并不是因为
Surely all of this isn't because
他们想终止婚礼
they want to stop a marriage.
我们应该感谢他们的帮助
We should welcome their help.
伊兰
Elaan.
伊兰，两颗行星
Elaan, two planets,
和整个恒星系统的稳定都指望它
an entire star system's stability depends on it.
我们有责任忘记发生的事情
We have a duty to forget what happened.
你能做到吗？
Could you do that?
你能把我给另一个男人吗？
Could you give me to another man?
你我收到的命令
My orders and yours
都说你属于另一个男人
say that you belong to another man.
发生的事情…
What happened ...
是个意外
was an accident.
不是意外
It was no accident.
我选择了你，你也选择了我
I chose you, and you chose me.
我有个计划
I have a plan.
有了这艘船，你可以彻底消灭特洛伊乌斯
With this ship, you could completely obliterate Troyius.
然后就没有结婚的必要了
Then there will be no need for the marriage.
出于感激
And in gratitude,
我的人民会让你统治整个星系
my people will give you the complete rule of this system.
什么样的头脑会想到这样的事情？
What kind of a mind could think of such a thing?
他是特洛伊人
He's a Troyian.
[对讲机蜂鸣]
[Intercom Buzzes]
[蜂鸣]
[Buzz]
[史波克] 舰长？
[Spock] Captain?
你无法抗拒我的爱，亲爱的
You cannot resist my love, my love.
舰长？
Captain?
[开门]
[Door Opens]
我们可以见你一会儿吗？
May we see you a moment?
吉姆
Jim.
吉姆，我们可以和你说句话吗？
Jim, may we please have a word with you?
舰长，你没事吧？
Captain, are you all right?
她哭了吗，吉姆？
Did she cry, Jim?
什么？
What?
她哭了吗？
Did she cry?
她的眼泪有没有碰到你？
Did her tears touch you at any time?
噢，我们有麻烦了
Oh, we're in trouble.
吉姆，佩特里告诉克莉丝汀
Now listen, Jim, Petri told Christine
伊拉希亚女人的眼泪里有一种生化物质
the Elasian women have a biochemical substance in their tears
就像超级爱情药水一样
that acts like a super love potion.
根据佩特里的说法，它不会消失
According to him, it doesn't wear off.
那么是真的吗，舰长？
It is true then, Captain?
这是真的
It's true.
老骨头，你得给我找个解药
Bones, you've got to find me an antidote.
我会试试，我需要测试
I'll try. I'll need tests.
[对讲机哨声]
[Intercom Whistles]
[苏鲁] 舰桥呼叫舰长
[Sulu] Bridge to Captain.
我是舰长
Captain here.
舰长，克林贡飞船改变了航向
Captain, the Klingon ship has changed course.
它正以曲速向我们飞来
It is heading toward us at warp speed.
我来了
On my way.
进入战斗岗位
Battle stations.
[警报声]
[Alarm Sounds]
[开门]
[Door Opens]
相位炮待命
Phasers stand by.
相位炮准备好了，长官
Phasers ready, sir.
他们的速度超过曲速6，舰长
Their speed is better than warp 6, Captain.
契科夫先生，设定航线
Mr. Chekov, lay in a course
把我们带出这个星系
to take us out of this star system.
如果他们想打一架
If they want to fight,
让我们有一些回旋余地
Let's get some maneuvering room.
航线已计算，长官
Course computed, sir.
已设定，舰长
Laid in, Captain.
好的，前进，曲速2
All right. Ahead warp factor 2.
[斯科提] 舰长，物质-反物质…
[Scotty] Captain, the matter- antimatter ...
搁置该命令，什么，斯科提？
Belay that order. What, Scotty?
物质-反物质舱被设置为
The antimatter pods are rigged to blow up
在我们进入曲速驱动时爆炸
the moment we go into warp drive.
斯科提，那个炸弹……你能拆除吗？
Scotty, that bomb ... can you dismantle it?
不能，会被被炸飞
Not without being blown across the galaxy.
给我脉冲引擎的
Give us every ounce of power you can
所有动力
from the impulse drive.
找到炸弹的解决方案，通话完毕
Find a solution to the bomb. Kirk out.
苏鲁先生，操控敏捷一点
Mr. Sulu, stand by to make your maneuvers smartly.
她反应有些迟钝
She'll be sluggish on response.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
10万公里…
100,000 kilometres.
90…
90.
80…
80.
相位炮，听我的命令准备发射
Phaser crews, stand by to fire on command.
60.
准备
Ready.
50.
先别开火
Hold your fire.
她没有发射就从我们身边经过了
She's passed us without firing a shot.
我认为他们不打算攻击我们
I don't think they meant to attack us.
这次，我们很幸运
We were very fortunate this time.
是的，他们的战术现在很清楚了，史波克先生
Yes, their tactics are quite clear now, Mr. Spock.
他们想让我们切到曲速引擎
They were trying to make us cut in warp drive.
然后我们会炸毁自己
That way we'd have blown ourselves up
并帮他们解决他们的问题
and solved their problem for them
避免和联邦开战的风险
without risking war with the Federation.
非常利索
Very neat.
你是对的，但为什么克林贡人
You're right. But why do the Klingons
认为占有这个星系这么重要？
consider the possession of this system so vital?
是的，很好的问题，史波克先生
Yes, a very good question, Mr. Spock.
我还有个问题，舰长
I have another question, Captain.
多尔曼不应该远离舰桥吗？
Is not the bridge the wrong place for the Dohlman
在这种时候
at a time like this?
我自有判断……
I'll be the judge ...
是的，你…
Yes, you're ...
你说得很对
you're quite right.
谢谢，史波克先生
Thank you, Mr. Spock.
我要你去医务室
I want you to go to Sick Bay.
它是船上最安全的地方
It's the best protected part of the ship.
我希望能在你身边
I want to be by your side.
你在这儿会干扰我的效率…
Your presence here is interfering with my efficiency ...
和我保护你的能力
my ability to protect you.
史波克先生，你来掌舵
Mr. Spock, you have the con.
五号甲板
Deck five.
我爱你
I love you.
我选择了你
I have chosen you,
我仍然不明白你为什么不与克林贡人开战
and still I don't understand why you didn't fight the Klingon.
如果我能通过逃跑来完成我的使命，
If I can accomplish my mission by turning tail and running,
我会很乐意这样做
I'll gladly do that.
那个任务是带我去特洛伊乌斯？
And that mission is to take me to Troyius.
是的
Yes.
你会让我为另一个男人穿上婚纱
Would you have me wearing my wedding dress for another man
并且再也不见你吗？
and never see you again?
是的，伊兰
Yes, Elaan.
你对这样的设想感到高兴吗？
Are you happy at the prospect?
不
No.
[对讲机哨声]
[Intercom Whistles]
斯科特呼叫舰长
Scott to Captain.
我是柯克
Kirk here.
我有一个坏消息，舰长
I've got bad news, Captain.
整个二锂晶体转换器组件熔毁了
The entire dilithium crystal converter assembly is fused.
不可能修复了
No chance of repair.
完全没用了
It's completely unusable.
不可能恢复曲速引擎？
No chance of restoring warp drive?
没有二锂晶体就不可能
Not without dilithium crystals.
我们甚至不能产生足够的能量来发射武器
We can't even generate enough power to fire our weapons.
通话完毕
Kirk out.
伊兰，我得回舰桥
Elaan, I have to go back to the bridge.
请你你务必去医务室
Please, you must go to Sick Bay.
是的，亲爱的
Yes, my love.
测试24，三氧化釦在钣溶液中
Test number 24. Colladium trioxide in algobarium solution.
结果也是阴性
Results also negative.
医生
Doctor,
没有药物能解伊拉希亚人眼泪的毒
there is no antidote to the poison of Elasian tears.
几百年来，伊拉斯的男人
The men of Elas have tried desperately
拼命试图消除它的力量
for centuries to dispel its power.
你在浪费时间，医生
You're wasting your time, Doctor.
浪费的也是我的时间，大使
It is my time to waste, Ambassador.
医生，船长让我来这里，安全起见
Doctor, the captain asked me to come here for safety.
安全？
Safety?
医生，你估计我们的生存几率是多少？
What is your estimate of our chances for survival, Doctor?
这是舰长的责任，大使
That is the captain's responsibility, Ambassador.
舰长，来自克林贡飞船的消息
Captain, message from the Klingon ship.
他们命令我们等待登船或被摧毁
They're ordering us to stand by for boarding or be destroyed.
他们要求立即答复
They demand an immediate reply.
他们试图逼我们开战
They're trying to force a fight.
斯科提，我们的动力状态如何？
Scotty, what's our energy status?
93%的脉冲动力，长官
93% of impulse power, sir.
我们仍然可以机动飞行
We can still maneuver.
机动飞行？是的
Maneuver? Aye.
我们可以像垃圾船一样
We can wallow like a garbage's cow
绕着一艘曲速驱动的星际飞船打滚
against a warp-driven starship.
我们的护盾能坚持几个回合
Our shields will hold for a few passes,
但没有物质-反物质反应堆
but without the matter- antimatter reactor,
我们没有机会
we've no chance.
舰长，在这种紧急情况下你不能呼叫星际舰队吗？
Captain, can you not call Starfleet on this emergency?
让克林贡人知道他们成功地摧毁了我们的曲速引擎？
And let the Klingons know they succeeded in wiping out our warp engines?
在企业号被摧毁前援兵无法到达
Help could not arrive before the Enterprise was destroyed.
既然我们都要死了
Now that we are all about to die,
我再次请求你接受这条项链
I ask you once again to accept this necklace,
并佩戴它
and to wear it
作为尊重的象征
as a token of respect
为了你我的人民的最后愿望
for the desperate wishes of your people and mine
为了和平
for peace.
你们其他世界的男人只会说
That's all you men of other worlds can speak of,
责任和义务
duty and responsibility.
我们会拖延时间
We'll stall for time.
保持航线，希望能唬住克林贡人
Proceed on course and hope the Klingons can be bluffed,
或者他们没有做好全面战争的准备
or that they're not prepared for a general war.
打开呼叫频率
Open a hailing frequency.
频率已打开，长官
Frequency open, sir.
我是联邦星舰企业号的
This is Captain James Kirk
詹姆斯·柯克舰长，正在处理联邦事务
of the U.S.S. Enterprise on Federation business.
我们的使命是和平的
Our mission is peaceful,
但我们不会接受任何干涉
but we're not prepared to accept any interference.
企业号，准备被登船或摧毁
Enterprise, prepare to be boarded or destroyed.
我想说我们的策略并不完全有效
I'd say our strategy wasn't totally effective.
舰长，克林贡飞船正接近
Captain, the Klingon ship is closing
拦截航线
on an intercept course.
50万千米
500,000 kilometres.
升起护盾
Deflector shields up.
斯科提，你能分部分能量给相位炮吗？
Scotty, can you give me partial power on the phaser banks?
不，长官，不可能
No, sir, not a chance.
30万千米
300,000 kilometres.
我告诉过你留在医务室
I told you to stay in Sick Bay.
我想和你一起死
I want to die with you.
我们不会死的
We're not going to die.
现在离开舰桥
Now get off the bridge.
[苏鲁] 10万千米
[苏鲁] 100,000 kilometres.
他掠过了我们，保持护盾升起
He's past us. All shields held.
苏鲁先生，前往143，标记2
Mr. Sulu, bring her to 143 mark 2.
保持我们前护盾对着他
Keep our forward shields to him.
他又来了，长官
Here he comes again, sir.
稳住
Stay with the controls.
保持我们前护盾对着他
Keep our forward shields to him.
超过曲速7
Better than warp 7.
满舵，苏鲁！掉头！
Hard over, Sulu. Bring her around.
他朝我们的侧翼来了
He's going for our flank.
苏鲁！
Sulu!
对不起，舰长，用脉冲引擎反应不够快
Sorry, Captain. She won't respond fast enough on impulse.
他又掠过我们了
He's past us again.
4号护盾受损
Damage to number four shield.
多严重？
How bad?
它无受再一次承受进攻，舰长
It will not withstand another full charge, Captain.
我得到了一些非常奇特的能量读数
I'm getting some very peculiar energy readings.
他又和我们平行了
He's paralleling us again.
他似乎中断了攻击
He seems to have broken off the attack.
什么样的读数，史波克先生？
What sort of readings, Mr. Spock?
她是源头
She is the source.
伊兰？
Elaan?
项链
The necklace.
这里面是什么宝石？
What kind of jewels are in this?
他们叫它拉丹斯
They call them radans.
项链应该会给你带来好运
The necklace is supposed to bring you luck.
它的价值不大
It is of little value.
它们是普通的石头
They are common stones.
这些是普通石头？
These are common stones?
看到了吗，舰长？
See, Captain?
这里和这里
Here and here.
普通石头？
Common stones?
现在我明白为什么克林贡人对这个星系感兴趣了
Now I see why the Klingons are interested in this system.
可以给我吗？
May I have this?
当然，如果我能帮上忙的话
If I can be of any help, of course.
你也许能救了我们的命
You may have Just saved our lives.
史波克先生，你认为斯科提可以利用二锂晶体吗？
Mr. Spock, do you think Scotty could make use of dilithium crystals?
毫无疑问，舰长
No doubt, Captain.
[苏鲁] 他又过来了，长官
[Sulu] He's coming in again, sir.
苏鲁先生，准备好听我的命令
Mr. Sulu, prepare on my order
迅速转向左舷
to turn quickly to port.
尝试保护4号护盾
Try and protect the number four shield.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
现在，苏鲁，左满舵！
Now, Sulu. hard to port!
护盾还在但是减弱了，长官
Shields holding, but weakened, sir.
舰长
Captain.
有消息
Message coming in.
[克林贡] 企业号，我们的读数证实你们的能量极低，
[Klingon] Enterprise, our readings confirm your power extremely low,
你们的护盾在变形
your shields buckling.
这是你们最后的投降机会
This is your last chance to surrender.
舰长，4号护盾刚刚破裂了
Captain, number four shield just collapsed.
脉冲动力下降到31%
Impulse power down to 31%.
乌乎拉上尉，打开呼叫频率
Lieutenant Uhura, open a hailing frequency.
频道已打开，长官
Channel open, sir.
这是联邦星舰企业号的
This is Captain James Kirk
詹姆斯·柯克舰长
of the United Spaceship Enterprise.
我可以提投降条件吗？
May I request your terms for surrender?
没有条件
No terms.
必须立即无条件投降
Surrender must be unconditional and immediate.
斯科提，你的估计？
Scotty, your estimate.
我们正在安装，长官
We're fitting it now, sir,
但是我们必须运行测试
but we'll have to run tests to make sure.
在实战中测试吧
Test it in combat.
舰长，这些是粗水晶
Captain, these are crude crystals.
无法判断不规则的形状会对能量流有什么影响
There's no way to judge what the unusual shapes will do to the energy flow.
它们可能炸飞我们……
That could blow us up ...
安装完毕通知我
Let me know when it's in place.
打开呼叫频率
Open a hailing frequency.
打开了，长官
Hailing frequency open, sir.
这是企业号
This is the Enterprise.
你能保证我们的乘客伊拉斯的多尔曼的安全吗？
Will you guarantee the safety of our passenger, the Dohlman from Elas?
没有条件
No conditions.
立即投降
Surrender immediately.
舰长，他开始行动了
Captain, he's starting his run.
[对讲机哨声]
[Intercom Whistles]
斯科特呼叫舰长，安装完毕，长官
Scott to Captain. It's in place, sir,
但后果怎样我不负责
but I can't answer for what happens.
你和史波克上来
You and Spock get up here.
苏鲁，准备进行曲速机动飞行
Sulu, prepare for warp maneuvers.
是，长官
Aye, sir.
契科夫，装备光子鱼雷
Chekov, arm photon torpedoes.
光子鱼雷已准备
Photon torpedoes ready.
曲速动力分配给护盾，舰长？
Warp power to the shields, Captain?
不，他的传感器会检测到我们的能量增加
Negative. His sensors will pick up our power increase.
他越认为我们无法反击
The more helpless he thinks we are,
他就会越靠近
the closer he'll come.
当他经过时，我想切入曲速引擎
As he passes, I want to cut in warp drive.
我们将在曲速2时转身，所有武器瞄准
We'll pivot at warp 2 and bring all tubes to bear.
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
契科夫先生，向他大范围发射
Mr. Chekov, give him a full spread
光子鱼雷
of photon torpedoes.
是的，舰长
Aye, Captain.
10万千米
100,000 kilometres.
斯科提，准备好切入曲速引擎
Scotty, stand by to cut in warp drive.
有波动
Fluctuation.
因为晶体的形状
It's the shape of the crystals.
我就怕这个
I was afraid of that.
75…
75.
70…
70.
60…
60.
50…
50.
在最小射程开火
Fire at minimum range.
40.
她不会稳定下来
She won't steady down.
30…
30.
进入曲速，斯科提，所有动力转到护盾
Warp in, Scotty. Full power to shields.
曲速2
Warp factor 2.
设定航线148，标记3
Lay us a course 148 mark 3.
契科夫
Chekov,
光子鱼雷，发射
photon torpedoes fire!
是的，长官
Aye, sir.
直接击中飞船中部
Direct hit amidships by photon torpedo.
克林贡3号盾牌损坏
Damage to Klingon number three shield.
4号盾牌被摧毁
Number four shield obliterated.
失去飞行能力
Loss of maneuver power.
他严重受损，舰长
He's badly damaged, Captain.
继续以低速驶离
Continuing away at reduced speed.
解除战斗部署
Secure from general quarters.
干得好，苏鲁先生
Well done, Mr. Sulu.
斯科提
Scotty.
但我不明白
But I don't understand you.
你的意思是你不会追赶并消灭他？
You mean you won't pursue and finish him off?
不
No.
苏鲁先生，继续去特洛伊乌斯的航线
Mr. Sulu, resume course for Troyius.
是的，长官
Aye, aye, sir.
你不传送下去参加仪式吗？
You will not beam down for the ceremony?
不
No.
我希望你拿着这个
I want you to have this
作为私人纪念品
as a personal memento.
我了解到在特洛伊乌斯上
I have learned that on Troyius,
他们不戴这样的东西
they do not wear such things.
记住我
Remember me.
我别无选择
I have no choice.
我也没有
Nor have I.
我只有责任和义务
I have only responsibilities and obligations.
再见
Good-bye.
传送
Energize.
现在已经稳定了
It's stabilized now.
史波克，我已经分离出了伊拉希亚眼泪的生化物质
Spock, I've isolated the biochemical substance of the Elasian tears.
它是一种感染
It's a kind of infection,
我想我找到了解药
and I think I found an antidote.
太晚了，医生
Too late, Doctor.
舰长已经找到了他自己的解药
The captain has found his own antidote.
你的瓦肯脑子坏了吗？
Are you out of your Vulcan mind?
你知道我工作了多久吗…
Do you know how long ...
伊拉斯女人的解药是一艘星舰
The antidote to a woman of Elas is a star ship.
企业号在多尔曼之前就感染了舰长
The Enterprise infected the captain before the Dohlman.
苏鲁先生，准备把我们带出轨道
Mr. Sulu, prepare to take us out of orbit.
嗯，我严重怀疑
Well, I doubt seriously
企业号是否有任何解药
if there's any kind of an antidote for the Enterprise.
在这个特殊案例中，医生
In this particular instance, Doctor,
我同意你的看法
I agree with you.
以曲速2前进
Ahead warp factor 2.